Guide to the Barry family papers, 1793-1956.
Barry family papers, 1793-1956.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Barry family papers, 1793-1956.
1859
.3 cubic ft.
Account books, correspondence, deeds, a justice dockett, trade cards, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of the Charles H. Barry family of Pittstown, Rensselaer County, New York, include family, store, and blacksmith account books, 1806-79; a few personal letters and deeds; justice dockett, 1841-63; report on the condition of the Troy Turnpike, ca.1867; trade cards; and miscellaneous papers.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers of the Charles H. Barry family of Pittstown, Rensselaer County, New York, include family, store, and blacksmith account books, 1806-79; a few personal letters and deeds; justice dockett, 1841-63; report on the condition of the Troy Turnpike, ca.1867; trade cards; and miscellaneous papers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Barry family.; Barry, Charles H.
Subjects:
Toll roads.; Blacksmiths.
Places:
Pittstown (N.Y.); Rennselaer Co., N.Y.
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.; Deeds.; Dockets.; Trade cards.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Indenture made Mar. 7, 1793 between Lavinus Lansing and Addi Bigelow: receipts and transferals from Apr. 3, 1795-Sept. 11, 1801 written on back; land involved in Rensselaer County, NY, 1793 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Figures for dates June 30 and Aug. 7, 1801 refer to new shoes, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Smith Filkins to DLF Caw, Oct. 11, 1814 (1845?) Raymertown, Rensselaer County, refers to yard goods, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Counsellor at Law license for Andrew Thompson signed by Smith Thompson, Chief Justice of New York State, Jan. 15, 1817, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Summons to Seneca Bratt, Mar. 1, 1845, signed Charles H. Barry, Justice of the Peace, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Receipt of John Downey, Oct. 12, 1849, received by I.H. Barry (his committee), signed by John S. Van Valkenbergh (?) and John C. Mather (?), Commissioner of Loans, Troy, NY, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- General bills dated Sept. 5, 1852 and Jan. 22, 1853, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from H. Filkins (?) to his father, Mar. 28, 1853, Niagara Falls, NY, mentions "Mr. Barry", 1853 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Jno. S Barry to his brother Charles H. Barry, Apr. 18, 1853,New York City, concerning a loan, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sept. 5, 1852 and Aug. 1, 1853 bills to Abijah Downing and John Downing for carpentry, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Mr. Filkins to D.L.J. Caw, Sept. 4, 1854, in regard to tailoring, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Receipt signed by Charles H. Barry Jr., Apr. 13, 1858, acknowledginh payment by Jno. S. Barry, Constantine, Michigan, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Deed search, recorded May 10, 1859, mortgage last assigned to John S. Barry, originally land given to John Waltham - no town mentioned, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Summons, Dec. 16, 1862, signed Chas. H. Barry, Justice Peace, Pittstown, New York, against Mary E. Stover, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Statement by Chas. H. Barry certifying the recording of the mortgage of 1859, Oct. 17, 1863, Rensselaer County, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letter to Chas. H. Barry from Jno. S. Barry, May 3, 1864, Constantine, Michigan, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Indenture, Sept. 24, 1864, Leonidas A. Barry and wife to Chas. H. Barry, recorded Jan. 26, 1866, Rensselaer County, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Promisory note, May 8, 1866, signed Chas. H. Barry to pay $518.29 to Cornelia Francisco, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Application for the Alteration of a Highway - C.H. Barry, Mar. 23, 1867, addressed to Benjamin I. Carpenter and Alpha Hayner, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Statement report concerning road conditions of Troy Turnpike, Apr. 6, 1867 (first draft? no signatures), 1867 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Indenture made Sept. 26, 1868, between David Akin and Harmon Cole and Charles H. Barry, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Receipt of court costs from Charles H. Barry signed on Dec. 18, 1868 by J. Romeyn, Defendant's Attorney, in the case of Hiram Slocum against Chas. H. Barry, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter from Chas. H. Barry to his father, Jan. 12, 1871, Constantine, Michigan, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Certification-discharge of mortgage of Joseph Codd to C.H. Barry, Oct. 4, 1883, Saginaw County, Michigan, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter to Nelson McChesney, Pittstown, New York, from T.J.O. Hare, 16 Pearl St., New York City, July 24, 1885, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter to C.H.Barry, Raymertown, New York, from Chas. H. Barry Jr., Constantine, Michigan, May 19, 1890, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from C.H. Barry to his brother, Constantine, Michigan, June 30, 1891, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Receipt for digging grave of Lucy Button Estate, signed by Elmer E Hayner (Keeper of grounds), Pittstown, Nov. 9, 1891, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Printed to "Brother Philo" concerning a reunion of the Philo Organization signed by Burt Matteson (printed), Fairfield, New York, Feb. 19, 1894, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter to John S. Barry from Charles I. Webster, Troy, New York, May 26, 1900, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Fractional Warrant - The Missouri Pacific Railway Company, Dec. 9, 1909, New York City, for Helen B. Markham, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter Chas. H. Barry from C. H. Barry (Jr.), Constantine, Michigan (envelope dated Mar. 27, 1911), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter to Mr. Ball from Chas. H. Barry, Raymertown, New York, Sept. 4, 1911, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter (incomplete) to "Dear Cousins" from ? (signature missing); assume the letter was written by Chas. H. Barry because it is from Raymertown, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter from "Cupcake" to ?, Feb. 16, 1956 on Hotel Bristol, Cairo stationary (she was not there), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Card announcing 100th celebration dinner of birth of Alexander Humboldt - Charles H. Barrie written on back (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Memo - no date - a list of names - none of which have been mentioned above (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from Charles Barry to Santa Claus - no date (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Memo concerning funeral costs - no date - on back of Manufacturer's National Bank, Troy, New York, deposit slip (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Prescription from Eaton J. Gross, Veterinary Surgeon, Troy, New York, no date (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notes on Greek sculpture and a listing of other periosds written on Fort Edward (N.Y.) Collegiate Institute stationary (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "A Baby's letter" - a poem (?) by Baby to "dear old uncle" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Incomplete Bond stating debt of Hugh McChesney to Chas. H. Barry, both of Pittstown, New York (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 3 printed lists of candidates for various state and town offices (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 6 paper fragments from blacksmith account book with miscellaneous figures and names as follows: Joseph Foster, Simon V. Cook, James Robert, John Downing, S amuel Shiffer, John Shiffer, William Dunnby; on refers to a court case, mentions Herman Knickerbacker v. John Sam (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Account book of merchant - notations made of large quantities of silk, cotton goods, flour, coffee and occassionally bank stock which her bought ans sold. Also general summaries of cash at hand and expenditures concerning his store - Jan. 1, 1859-Jan. 1, 1869. Back pages filled with personnal accounts of farmer, (?), May 1871-Nov. 27, 1872, 1859-69 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Court record book of Chas. H. Barry - recording of damages and costs of various court cases over which he presided. Also includes a brief summary of each case - Feb. 23, 1841-Decenber 3, 1863. A lsit of his mother's aunts and uncles in back of book (Filkins and Van Dercook's), 1841-63 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Records of a personal account, apparently of amounts owed and paid to various firms and individuals. Barry's name mentioned several times near end of book - Mar. 12, 1847-Aug. 19, 1854. Some entries for 1856, but in different hand, 1847-54 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Pittstown Journal - "1830" - but actually 1833 - July 20-Oct. 30, 1833, 1806-57 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- A family account book - Apr. 1, 1873-Mar. 4, 1879, 1873-79 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Account book of blacksmith (?) makes frequent mention of shoe sets, hammers and mending of steel goods. Later on in book many notations refer to farm labor work and handy-man jobs - Apr. 16, 1806-Oct. 25, 1857 (worked for Charles H. Barry in year of 1840), 1806-57 (Box 1, Folder 12)